<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>static on Pablo de Juan Fidalgo</title><link>https://pabdj.github.io/tags/static/</link><description>Recent content in static on Pablo de Juan Fidalgo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Pablo de Juan Fidalgo</copyright><lastBuildDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 09:50:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pabdj.github.io/tags/static/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Advanced Static Techniques - x86 Disassembly</title><link>https://pabdj.github.io/posts/advanced-static-techniques-_-x86-disassembly/</link><pubDate>Mon, 19 Dec 2022 09:50:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pabdj.github.io/posts/advanced-static-techniques-_-x86-disassembly/</guid><description>This blog post collects some notes that I took while reading PMA Chapter 4. As it was not the first time dealing with assembly most of the concepts rang a bell.
Opcodes and Endianness Network data uses big-endian and an x86 program uses little-endian. Therefore, the IP address 127.0.0.1 will be represented as 0x7F000001 in big endian format (over the network) and 0x0100007F in little-endian format (locally in memory)
Registers General registers Some x86 instructions use specific registers by definition.</description></item><item><title>Basic Static Techniques - Notes &amp; Labs</title><link>https://pabdj.github.io/posts/basicstatictechniques_notesandlabs/basicstatictechniques_notesandlabs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 12:50:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pabdj.github.io/posts/basicstatictechniques_notesandlabs/basicstatictechniques_notesandlabs/</guid><description>Notes Hashing: A Fingerprint for Malware We will use HashCalc tool.
Finding Strings For this task we will use FLOSS (FLARE Obfuscated String Solver) tool
Packed and Obfuscated Malware Packed and obfuscated code will often include at least the functions LoadLibrary and GetProcAddress, which are used to load and gain access to additional functions. UPX: the Ultimate Packer for eXecutables Several Microsoft Windows functions allow programmers to import linked functions not listed in a program&amp;rsquo;s file header.</description></item></channel></rss>