<?xml version="1.0" encoding="utf-8" standalone="yes"?><rss version="2.0" xmlns:atom="http://www.w3.org/2005/Atom"><channel><title>basic on Pablo de Juan Fidalgo</title><link>https://pabdj.github.io/tags/basic/</link><description>Recent content in basic on Pablo de Juan Fidalgo</description><generator>Hugo -- gohugo.io</generator><language>en-us</language><copyright>© Pablo de Juan Fidalgo</copyright><lastBuildDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 12:50:58 +0530</lastBuildDate><atom:link href="https://pabdj.github.io/tags/basic/index.xml" rel="self" type="application/rss+xml"/><item><title>Basic Dynamic Techniques - Notes &amp; Labs</title><link>https://pabdj.github.io/posts/basicdynamictechniques_notesandlabs/basicdynamictechniques_notesandlabs/</link><pubDate>Sat, 17 Dec 2022 12:50:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pabdj.github.io/posts/basicdynamictechniques_notesandlabs/basicdynamictechniques_notesandlabs/</guid><description>Notes Running malware How to launch DLLs successfully in dynamic analysis: take a look at the Exports with CFF Explorer and afterwards run the following command C:\&amp;gt;rundll32.exe DLLname, Export arguments with one of the Export functions that have appeared in the static analysis. To convert the DLL file into an executable, modify the PE header wiping the IMAGE_FILE_DLL (0x2000) flag from the Characteristics field in the IMAGE_FILE_HEADER. DLL malware may also need to be installed as a service, sometimes with a convenient export such as InstallService, as listed in ipr32x.</description></item><item><title>Basic Static Techniques - Notes &amp; Labs</title><link>https://pabdj.github.io/posts/basicstatictechniques_notesandlabs/basicstatictechniques_notesandlabs/</link><pubDate>Thu, 08 Dec 2022 12:50:58 +0530</pubDate><guid>https://pabdj.github.io/posts/basicstatictechniques_notesandlabs/basicstatictechniques_notesandlabs/</guid><description>Notes Hashing: A Fingerprint for Malware We will use HashCalc tool.
Finding Strings For this task we will use FLOSS (FLARE Obfuscated String Solver) tool
Packed and Obfuscated Malware Packed and obfuscated code will often include at least the functions LoadLibrary and GetProcAddress, which are used to load and gain access to additional functions. UPX: the Ultimate Packer for eXecutables Several Microsoft Windows functions allow programmers to import linked functions not listed in a program&amp;rsquo;s file header.</description></item></channel></rss>